<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Andrew W. Lee</title>
    <link>https://drewlee.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Andrew W. Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 10:50:38 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://drewlee.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Experiment</title>
      <link>https://drewlee.com/2020/apple-watch-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 10:50:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drewlee.com/2020/apple-watch-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m always surprised when I catch myself sidetracked on my phone. I pick up my phone intending to authenticate myself for 2FA in mind. Then just moments later, I’m checking my Fantasy Basketball team or responding to text messages. I’m sure there’s a psychology phenomenon named after this. Maybe this behavior is just strongly conditioned like Pavlov’s metronome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there’s nothing wrong with taking breaks and using the phone to relax. But I get distracted and get sidetracked. So I got an Apple Watch to see if it helps, with the goal being to improve my focus and not try to be more efficient with my time. I do many non-productive things throughout the day that it seems silly to save a few minutes at work when I’m spending hours that same day playing Dota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like an iPhone, the Apple Watch is highly customizable. I’ve seen friends with them use it as just another device with the same notifications. I didn’t want this to be a substitute for an iPhone. I wanted it to complement it. I would still have my phone, and I would check it, just less regularly. After thinking about what type of notifications I wanted on my watch, this is what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;https://drewlee.com/images/urgent-actionable-matrix.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;2x2 Matrix with Urgent and Non-Urgent on X-axis, Actionable and Unactionable on Y-axis&#34; title=&#34;Urgent Actionable Matrix&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Urgent Actionable Matrix for Notifications&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s similar to the Eisenhower Matrix of Urgent Important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to see if getting an Apple Watch would decrease the number of times I get sidetracked, reduce phone usage, and improve my focus at work. I’ve had the watch for over two weeks now and things feel better. It feels like my overall screen time is down, and the number of pickups is down. Unfortunately, right now, iOS doesn’t store screen time metrics, so I’m not able to compare the past and present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, I have liked that the Apple Watch encourages physical wellness, but I’ll save that for another post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overfitting</title>
      <link>https://drewlee.com/2019/overfitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 16:15:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drewlee.com/2019/overfitting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Something I want to try is to move somewhere to be alone and to work on things. All I would need is my laptop.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend Sasa told me he was thinking about moving somewhere, to be alone and to work on personal projects. That all he needed was his laptop and the internet. This way he would be free from distractions and be able to fully focus on projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said to try renting a place for a weekend and try that out before committing to fully moving. That way you get the experience and you&amp;rsquo;ll have a better idea of if being alone is the missing factor in working on side projects. In other words, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a better idea of if not being alone is the reason you&amp;rsquo;re not working on projects without such a drastic change. Because it&amp;rsquo;s possible that he&amp;rsquo;s wrong and being alone isn&amp;rsquo;t the sole reason, and to move seemed like overfitting for something he thinks he needs to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while ago I was interested in doing machine learning stuff. Machine learning could be used in so many ways to do so many things and that&amp;rsquo;s what fascinated me. But instead of learning and practicing it, my first instinct was to research &amp;ldquo;what kind of computer should I build to do machine learning?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time I only had a 15&amp;rdquo; MacBook Pro and I knew that it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the hardware to run really big models fast. I was obsessed with building a computer specifically built for machine learning, yet I didn&amp;rsquo;t even get to a point where my laptop&amp;rsquo;s hardware was the issue. This is overfitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time researching Nvidia graphics cards because CUDA was the big thing. I looked at the differences in ram for GPUs and how it would affect the machine learning workflows I thought I would run. For example, the difference between a GTX 1080 and the GTX 980 was an astonishing 5GB of ram and that would allow me to run bigger models. I learned all these things about building computers that would work great for machine learning that I never did any machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the wanting to build a dedicated computer was overfitting. Instead, I should have just done machine learning stuff on my laptop. And yes it would have been slower doing computations on a CPU but at least I would have done something. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that the important thing anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. From Wikipedia: Overfitting is &amp;ldquo;the production of an analysis that corresponds too closely or exactly to a particular set of data, and may, therefore, fail to fit additional data or predict future observations reliably&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Rewards Cards</title>
      <link>https://drewlee.com/2019/on-rewards-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 17:49:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drewlee.com/2019/on-rewards-cards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A trap that I’ve fallen into is thinking I can earn when I spend, and to some extent that’s true. When I spend money using a rewards credit card such as the Chase Sapphire Reserve, I get rewarded with points. It’s classical conditioning in its purest sense. These points can be redeemed for travel and cash back. But am I actually earning when I spend?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer? It depends. I am earning when I use a rewards card to pay for necessities such as a doctor’s appointment. But what about for unnecessary purchases like another drink at happy hour? I will be rewarded for spending. But is spending the best way to earn money back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely not. It’s far more effective to save a dollar than to try and earn a dollar in rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you get 3 reward points per dollar spent that can be redeemed for 1.5 cent / point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and that a happy hour drink with tip and tax comes out to $12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you buy a drink, you’re down $12 but you earn 30 points (or 45 cents in rewards).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t buy a drink, you’re out the drink but you’re up $12 or 800 points. And how much do I have to spend to earn a dollar in rewards? $22.22.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The second time around applying for jobs</title>
      <link>https://drewlee.com/2018/the-second-time-around-applying-for-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 07:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drewlee.com/2018/the-second-time-around-applying-for-jobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In July, I accepted my second full-time job. Looking back, my first and second job hunt was quite different. I wrote this is to provide alternative viewpoints on what to look for when applying to companies and deciding between offers, especially for those starting in their careers —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#outline-1&#34;&gt;Factors I used to apply and decide between offers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#outline-2&#34;&gt;Other factors to consider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#outline-3&#34;&gt;Less obvious factors to consider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#outline-4&#34;&gt;On declining an offer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around I was more intentional about the companies I applied to. I wanted to make sure joining the company was something I wanted. And after working at a large corporation I knew I wanted to go back to something smaller. While I was deciding where to interview and ultimately where I’d work next, there were four key things I used to prioritize and evaluate companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;outline-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Key Factors That I Prioritized In A Company&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was that the company had a strong engineering culture. This meant there were opportunities for me to grow as an engineer both in my technical and non-technical skills. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second was that the company had a strong sense of culture. It’s easy for companies to have mission statements and quotes from employees on career pages, but it’s something else entirely for it to be something embodied by the employees. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third was a collaborative environment. Companies that treat engineers with reverence or treat them like code monkeys, to me, are signs of an uncollaborative environment. Successful companies are usually a product of many functions working together, and when engineers are treated differently it can get in the way of collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth and last was work-life balance. It’s great to be ambitious early in your career; it has compounding effects. But it’s great to have a life outside of the office as well. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally impact was on the list. Impact and mission statements tend to be cliches in recruiting pitches. Anything can be spun to be impactful. I like being able to observe the impact that I make. There’s enjoyment in being able to get a visceral reaction from people that are affected by the work that I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately deciding what to prioritize is a personal choice. It’s worth spending time upfront to think about what interests you as it will help decide between offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Other Factors To Consider&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compensation is a big part of any job offer. It’s worth thinking about compensation before getting any offer calls because it can easily shape your decision making progress. The allure of high salaries and compensation packages can be quite seductive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to compensation is the location of the role. Income tends to be adjusted relative to the cost of living. So a high salary in San Francisco isn’t necessarily better than a lower salary in a place with a lower cost of living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some questions to consider: what are your income needs and wants? What are your living preferences? And on the equity side, questions like: What is your risk profile? Depending on which stage a company you get into, equity can be a gamble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dive deeper into what your equity means if it’s important to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible for mature startups to fail, go through a down-round, or dilution. So your equity may not be worth what you think it is. There’s also a drastic difference between getting equity in a public company and a startup or a private company that is far away from a liquidity event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen internet communities like r/cscareerquestions or Blind place a high focus on total compensation (“TC”). It’s not healthy to tie your self-worth to your income or compensation, although it&amp;rsquo;s easy to conflate the two. At the end of the day, to each their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A last note about compensation: there is no right or wrong when it comes to prioritizing compensation over other factors. In the end, each person’s situation is different and there are always trade-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;outline-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Secondary Factors To Consider&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around I have also come to consider the less quantifiable benefits. At least in the San Francisco Bay Area, companies tend to offer perks like catered or subsidized meals, commuting stipends, gym subsidies, and learning budgets. The list can go on as companies can offer different benefits. It’s worth asking about all the benefits available to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re just getting into becoming independent, away from your parent’s or family’s support, things like health insurance, medical or health spending accounts, 401ks, and other investment and retirement options, are also things to look into. There’s a learning curve the first time around, especially if you’re still covered under your parents. But it gets easier the second time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important benefit is time off. Usually, this falls under vacation and holidays. It’s either a set amount of vacation days or it’s unlimited. There’s a lot written about unlimited PTO if you search for it, but in short, it doesn’t mean that you can take time off whenever you want nor does it mean you can take off months at a time. It’s worth asking companies that offer this, how employees use it. Questions to ask: How flexible is taking time off? What’s the average amount of time taken off per employee? If asking a person that works at that company, ask how many days did you take off last year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, the last and most secondary factory is the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You spend a tremendous amount of your waking life at work. And if it’s not in an environment that you enjoy and feels comfortable in, it&amp;rsquo;ll be harder to be happy and do your best work. In smaller organizations, it can be easier to find a sense of community as by the very nature it will be a smaller group. It’s also very possible that you may not fit in with the community and become alienated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For interns and new grads: I’ve found bigger companies and corporations tend to invest more in events and mixers for new grads because there are so many. If you’re moving to a new place this might be the basis of your friend group. For return offers made to previous interns, it’s possible that your experience as an intern will differ as a full-time employee. This is because companies intentionally invest to get interns to return as full time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;outline-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How To Handle Declining A Job Offer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People on the recruiting side understand other companies also want you and are okay with you declining an offer. You don’t get blacklisted for gracefully declining an offer, but you’ll get blacklisted for reneging an offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of your job hunt if you don’t end up at your dream company, don’t despair. Make the best out of your experience and try again later down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot can be learned to be at companies that experience a growth phase. For example, engineering and management processes that work for X employee count won’t work when there are X + Y employees. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture fit or introductory interviews with engineers are a great opportunity to learn more about what life would be like. Usually, you can ask these at the end of a technical interview, assuming there is time left. Ask the recruiting team you’re working with to set up time to talk with an engineer if you’re still unsure. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the chase for prestige and success might seem worth it early on, sacrificing youth for it, but you only have one life. And while you’re young and don’t have many attachments like a mortgage or a family it’s easier to explore more, do more, and see more. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Pledgemaster</title>
      <link>https://drewlee.com/2017/why-pledgemaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 20:09:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drewlee.com/2017/why-pledgemaster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Many people reading this won&amp;rsquo;t know what a pledge master is. It varies for each organization. In my experience, it is not at all what you would imagine from the movies like 22 Jump Street, with prospects being hazed and being forced to consume excess amounts of alcohol to join an organization. A better mental picture would be a camp counselor at summer camp, engaging in leading and helping the group to bond.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Being pledgemaster consists of leading and managing a group of individuals to improve themselves and bond over the course of a quarter at UCLA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was written for the bright and unique individuals I had the privilege of leading and managing with James. This is a reflection of my experience and some observations I&amp;rsquo;ve made between my pledging experience and my experience as pledgemaster. I believe some of my observations applies to any group of people that become closer together through concentrated shared experiences for a period of time like working on a startup that gets acquired.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I ran because I wanted to help people become entrepreneurs, in the sense that they develop the know-how to to take any idea in their mind and make it become a reality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I would have said if you asked me why I wanted to be a Pledgemaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with my own Pledgemasters, Theo and Jaz. I met with them privately towards the end of 7th week last spring. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what was said—it was not important. What was memorable was that during this meeting I saw the dedication my Pledgemasters had put in. Their time, their effort, and their thoughts were all on us. It was heartwarming and bizarre. Before, I had only seen them as Pledgemasters, not as two people. Seeing them there, sitting at a table in front of Bruin Cafe, in their normal clothes, I slowly began to register them as human beings. They had another meeting scheduled after mine ended, and it was in this moment, that I realized how they had sacrificed their Thursday to be there. They were so committed to pledge quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned from them Pledgemaster was a position of service and sacrifice. It was their hard work and sacrifice that inspired me to run for the position. Reflecting on this now, I benefitted so much from pledge quarter and I hope I was able to follow in their footsteps and make a similar positive impact in all of your lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When James and I began talking about what outcomes we wanted, the only idea I had was based on an email that one of my bosses sent to his colleagues at my first job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gang, my client is trying to do X and I’m not as experienced with it. Can you refer me people to reach out to? — Bob.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob, well Robert, had been out of law school for well over 20 years at that point. The fact that he still kept in touch with former classmates impressed me—so much so that he felt comfortable asking for their help years later. This is my hope for the Mu class, that even 5 or 10 years out, you stay connected. More importantly, I hope that you can depend on another when you need it most. To do this some of you must overcome your selflessness and become momentarily selfish. For others it will be working around your scheduled day to make time for your pledge class. For the rest it means patiently listening to and understanding what your pledge sibling is communicating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at UCLA, this will not be a big challenge. Actually, it should be pretty easy. You will see most of your pledge class during the school year. The real challenge begins when you are miles apart, in different timezones, and in different phases of your lives. It gets tough when you are no longer conveniently close to each other. This will be the real test. There is not much I can do now to make this happen since this is going to be in the future. I am hoping that your experiences during Hell Week and beyond will help to make this dream become a reality. That would be amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effortless way to stay together is to reminisce about pledge quarter. When you gather it will be the shared thread that keeps you sewn together. You remember the good times and the bad, the sleepovers and the kickbacks, the punishments, the pledge meetings. But the thread can only keep you bound for so long; time passes and these events will become history. The challenge becomes finding ways to stay together and to make new memories. It takes going out of your way to set up events with Mus, and going out of your way to make it a priority to attend them. The latter is actually more challenging than the former.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are all young adults soon to be living with your own set of priorities. SEP and your pledge class will lower in priority—it’s inevitable. It is not something sad, but just the way it is. Remembering to make a conscious and committed effort to your class is on you. If the Mus make it to the future still connected, let me know. The real test is if you are there at each other’s weddings. [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going into the future, there are things to remember if you are to survive as a group. The first is to not let resentment and discomfort build up. If you ignore a problem so that it creates a division, you won’t make it. That is a guarantee. The best choice of action, then, is to take up that uncomfortable conversation and address each other and your issue with love and patience. You all have practice doing this. The second is to not give up on another. Be patient and loving towards your pledge class. You are the biggest pledge class and there is strength in your numbers. Stay together, work together, and as a group you will be unstoppable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve half jokingly said that being pledgemaster twice is the way to go. The first time around you learn so much and make mistakes. So the second time around you can improve on it. Thinking further, I believe pledgemaster should be done once. And only once. All of the little mistakes, the hiccups, and last minute planning is characteristic of pledge quarter. It’s the perfect microcosm of entrepreneurship. Nothing is perfect, and rarely does something go according to plan. [2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this journey has come to an end and Tim and Jayleen are the new Pledgemasters. Reflecting back, the reasons why I ran for pledgemaster have changed. Transforming you into entrepreneurs was my goal, but it’s become so much more. Being a part of your journey has become the most fulfilling reason for being pledgemaster. It’s the things that I had never expected, that have made being pledgemaster so worth it. [3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, seeing many of you so close and comfortable with each other makes me truly grateful for the opportunity. I will make it a priority to be available to you all for the remaining time I have here. Feel free to send me a message to hang out. I really mean it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] It’s rather arbitrary, but I think it’s a good benchmark for when you know you have all made it. If this happens, be sure to send me and James wedding invitations as well. I’m sure we’d love to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] More often than not there were things I would have never anticipated. That’s life and you can’t predict it. So you just go with the flow of things when things don’t go according to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Me and James have remarked on how we would have never guessed that for some of you, having a pledge class created a significant difference to your UCLA experience. And we would have never guessed how much SEP and your pledge class would be such a big part of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>